Good morning and welcome to build twenty sixteen
it fantastic to be back here in san francisco welcome
to everyone here with us as well as everyone joining us on the web.
You know, for me it feels like I've marked all my adult life
with microsoft developer conferences in fact when I think about even the but
the might children I think about the various platform eras at microsoft
all my son belongs to ys
and my daughters are all dot net and it's so it's so
fantastic to be back here and talking to developers there's one thing
that's so unique about developer conferences developers
come here excited already about technology they get to
see more technology meet more people who are talking technology
most importantly they walk away inspired.
By what they see they learn to build even more
cooler technology that uniqueness of developer conferences
is what we want to celebrate here over the next three days
that ability of developers to amplify technology is what we want
to talk about a over the course of this conference at build.
Talking about all of this technology.
In fact there is a much more mainstream dialogue.
About the role of technology.
In our society.
And, it's the right time to have that dialogue because technologies so much more
mainstream it's embedded in our daily lives
it's embedded in our companies in our industries in our economies
and countries much more so than ever before.
So, we have these.
Profound questions and issues in front of us.
technology driving economic growth for everyone?
Or is economic growth stalled in spite?
Of technological spend.
Is technology empowering people or is it displacing us?
Is technology helping us preserve our enduring values such as
privacy?
Or is it compromising it?
These are the issues that are being discussed and their the
right issues for us to have a broad dialogue not just in one
company not just in one of our industry but as a society.
I m a optimist.
We as a company.
Are optimistic about what technology can
do for us I believe technology can
in fact drive economic growth all over the world?
I believe technology can empower us.
I believe technology can be used to preserve our enduring values.
We do however have to make choices how we go about building
technology.
We need to make design choices.
Economic choices and social choices.
That ensure.
That the way we build technology the way we use technology helps
us make progress as a society that optimism.
And, that several choices is embedded
encoded in our mission to empower every person
and every organization on the planet to achieve more.
want to make things so that others.
Can make things and make things happen?
That is our broad platform approach.
And, when we think about driving success?
And, empowering people and businesses through digital
technology.
We have to start with all of you as developers we have
to empower you with technology but more importantly we have to
create that opportunity for you to be able to express your
creativity.
That can change the world and throughout this developer conference that's what we want to talk
about the platforms that
you get to work on that really.
Are going to help you change the world?
We live in a mobile-first cloud-first world we've talked
about this many times before but it's always good to go back to make sure.
That we are grounded in what we mean by mobile-first cloud-first.
For us mobile first is not about the mobility of any single device
it is the mobility of the human experience across all the devices
that all the computing in our lives.
Cloud is not a single destination.
Cloud is a new form of computing.
That in fact enables that mobility of experience across all our devices
it infuses those experiences with intelligence because it has the
ability to reason over large amounts of data using a distributed computing
fabric that's what is the rich mobile-first cloud-first world for which we are building.
And, we are building three interconnected platforms.
To morrow
you want to hear from struck got three about our intelligent cloud and azure.
Scott's going to talk about extensively
how for all of the new application patterns starting with
iot ttwo mobile to web to machine learning how
you can use data and infrastructure to build these
applications more importantly he's going to talk about how.
Building
more azure gives you the opportunity to reach over five
million businesses that are already in azure active directory.
Qi lu is going to talk tomorrow about the opportunity with office
three-six five.
We're opening up office three-six five unlike ever before your
applications your data to office three-six five connectors.
And, add-ins can be found within
the ui scaffolding of office very naturally by the users of office.
That is one-point-two billion users of office
ultimately will be able to get access to all of your applications because they get
built-in to the ui scaffolding we also want to take the rich
semantic information underneath office that is people their relationships
this schedules their files and all the other artifacts
and expose it as microsoft graph so that you can use it
you can extended as part of your applications
so cheese want to talk about what that rich world looks like.
And, this morning.
Cherry and I will talk about more personal computing.
Windows ten is off.
To an amazing start.
It's the fastest-growing version of windows both consumers and
enterprises.
We have tremendous innovation in device.
In fact it's new categories of windows devices whether they are iot
t or hololens are getting created.
And, this morning you'll hear from terry in team
about all of the advances with windows how
we are bringing the natural user interface whether it be touch.
Ink voice.
Or even image recognition.
So, that you can use them to build new categories of applications.
We also want to talk about how.
In gaming and consumptive applications we're going to open up
both the pc and the consul for new opportunities for developers.
We also going to talk about how windows is your ultimate
dev box where you can do all your application development
for windows and beyond right there on a windows pc.
We also want to talk about our new emerging platform.
Where in a very early days of this it's actually the into section?
Of all of our three ambitions recall it conversations as a platform.
It's a simple concept yet it's very powerful its impact
is about taking the our of human language.
applying it more pervasively to all of our computing.
That means we need to infuse into our computers and
computing intelligence, intelligence about us and our context.
And, by doing so we think.
This can have asked profound an impact as the previous platform shifts
of had whether it be gui whether it be the web
are touch on mobile.
So, we'll have extensive conversation about the beginning of this new platform journey but
we want to get started with windows ten and what that opportunity
represents to all of you and do that let me please welcome terry myerson up on stage thank you?
Samoa.
So, excited to be back here and
filled with all of you I mean it really is such a great time to be
a windows developer and today it's going to get even better.
Satya shared our ambition with windows is the make
computing more personal and change the way all of us interact with.
An benefit from technology enabling us interact with devices more
intuitively
using natural language conversations.
Evolving us mechanical keyboard and mouse.
Talks.
And, beyond taking advantage
more human capabilities like our voice
hence our face gestures fingerprints.
Expanding beyond today's pcs and phones.
Bringing computing into our world.
With holograms immersing ourselves in games across devices.
Windows ten is our home for
this evolution making all of us more productive enabling us to have more fun.
Windows tennis been out for eight months.
Is already being actively used by over two hundred seventy million people?
And, customers are more engaged than ever before
spending over seventy five billion hours on windows ten.
And, our hardware partners they have launched over
five hundred new devices designed for windows tans devices with large
screens small screens no screens and everything in between.
Or humbled by this response across the globe and do by?
Here right here in san francisco.
Now of.
This momentum it's not just can windows tennis after the
fastest adoption of any release of windows ever and
is not just consumers its enterprise customers also
consider just the united states department of defense for million device form
million devices will upgrade to windows tend just this year?
So, on behalf of the entire windows team were happy to welcome all of these
customers to windows ten where they have a brand-new pc
five-year-old pc.
Or brand-new mac join us to welcome on windows ten.
Now every day we're working hard on making windows ten better to
delight our users all around the world.
And, today
was so excited to share with you what we've been working on the next wave of innovations
are microsoft's the anniversary update to windows ten
coming this summer for free all of our windows ten customers.
Samoa.
How many of your windows insiders?
One windows insiders out there.
So, awesome I mean from bald team this things again you guys
helped shape everything we're doing
that microsoft giving us feedback every day on every pixel every ounce of
performance we can squeeze and of course today you can go download the latest
builds and give us feedback and everything we're talking about today with this
anniversary update more personal computing really does come to life more.
That windows hello.
Today you
can more securely and easily log into your device than ever before.
But, with this anniversary update now going to be able to use this secure and
easy biometric authentication with your apps or even better
with microsoft edge now be the first and only browser to
support this secure and easy biometric authentication to all of the supporting websites.
The anniversary update will introduce of all-new windows ink experience our goal is to
make using a pan with your device as seamless and as easy as pen and paper.
We designed this anniversary update will come to your xbox one now
bring all of your windows applications into your living room
and enabling you to turn on any retail xbox one
into a dev kit and of course the anniversary update will come the hololens
enabling all new ways to work communicate learn and play.
And, cortana in the anniversary update
to be incredibly new ways to get stuff done.
So, please welcome bryan showed you bryan roper do a demo of the anniversary update.
Thank you terry.
Ladies and gentlemen how you're feeling this morning man this through this I
was luxurious not a chance now how you feeling.
The awesome now with this anniversary update man I'm
pumped we're going to completely modernize the pc we're going to make it safer
and more secure we're going to make it more personal and productive and we're going to keep
you really engages with is more personal computing idea I want to start with
that safer and more secure all right make some noise if you use windows hello today.
You remember we launched this man biometric authentication with enterprise grade keeping folks secure the
most personal things possible your finger your face it's awesome we see folks loving this
artist coming the apps people are buying things in the windows store using this dropbox integrated
but today I want to talk about another part its very excited that's us a all right
there the largest financial service provider to our us military and they're actually going to
extend hello support for their website using microsoft edge because the new
final spectrum wthree-c implemented in edge this convenience and security
of edge can actually light up here so, check it out we're going to say the website now
this is so easy amount of device right now to roll my fingerprint are going to do
is touch log on windows hello you go up and, now it's asking me
to touch my fingerprint and just like this it logs in its that fast it's easy it's
safe and secure.
We are pumped about it.
Now let's talk about more personal computing and get a little bit productive here
right terry mentioned a new experiences that put ink front and center
all right we're going to help you with windows ink create ideate and collaborate better
okay app and why we do this bryan why would you put ink front and center because
allow you are still use pen and paper make some noise if you still write stuff down all the time on pen and paper?
Why do we do that we do it credits fast it's easy it's right there it's a media it
doesn't require setup but then sometimes lose that piece of paper and, you know, you
our man where was that so our goal of windows ink is really combine
that the naturalness and the speed of pen and paper the power-pc this four parts this number one we're going to
put this pen front and center so, you know, what to do with it number two we're going to make sure that we solve
the task that people are reaching for pen and paper most for a number three I'm going to show you how windows ink is actually
a deeper platform that enables faster and more fluid ink flow throughout the entire windows
experience all right so let's start with that first one putting the pen front and center ok so when I got my pen I
was super excited but I wasn't always sure what to do that are which app to use so we're solving for that
I'm going to push this pen button check this out this is the ink workspace
all things ink are here these are the three tasks people do most I'm going to jump in on that in a second but
look at this my most recently used pen apps I can get right back in and do what I was doing also down here tips and tricks
users are going to know what to do this pen we're going to walk you through that another thing I want to call out to you folks this right here
suggested apps this is one place where if I touch this I'm going to go
to us dedicated section of the store that just is amazing apps support pen our so we're going to
light up for folks going to know what to do with the pen we put it right front and center what you think about that?
Under getting started right.
What about the tasks we do most
number-one we jot down things to remember make some noise if you use sticky notes in your life?
I'm not surprised all right up three-m
sells fifty billion sticky notes a year all right so they on windows san we have
eight million monthly active users of sticky notes and three million daily active users so of course
we're going to make this better I think it's my sticky notes right here check this out here I had some stuff
had to make sure I showed you guys were doing good on that so far but watch this I'm going
to make a new note here my mom always gets worried when I do demos because me, you know,
she speaks spanglish she mixes it up were latins earlier bryan I'm worried that demo
good how you feeling I got always number common mom after this I want to make sure that
tomorrow call mom but watch what happens when I write
tomorrow okay look first of all look how easy and smooth this ink is flowing but
watch what happens next I wrote the word tomorrow because we're combining the our the pen and the pc you see it turn blue
that's because we're smart enough to know that was handwriting to know that it was a day so if I touch it my homey who rocks
at reminders cortana is easily able to come up and actually set that reminder for me ok and
beyond just setting reminders cortana bing is integrate will be able to recognize places up
europe maps this is going to be very smart these sticky notes are geniuses what you guys think about that.
Why else do we write things down sometimes when you scratch out idea
it's is easier to communicate visually how many times
are moving furniture you rip off a piece of paper you start jotting on
it you devs I know you run-up to the white board and write a bunch of stuff and then at the end of like all-white let me photograph
the white board and later try to decipher what those things were that made sense at the time
ok so we want to make sure you have a way to do that and that's why there's a sketch pad now so check this
out the sketch pad already wrote some stuff here for you and what you're going to see is I
wrote of course windows loves ink can I get a all you'll nodded that nice it
was smoothing buttery so check this out while so we put ink front and center I'm going to hit
you with some stats here we did a little survey of found out that seventy two percent
of people are still use pen and paper or various writing instruments a lot
less seventy two percent the user for actually more
than one hour per day that's crazy all right now of that seven in will that
seventy two percent now thirty two percent actually use it for more
than three hours a day so there's a lot of people using pen all right now check
how did that it was quick it was easy was immediate I got there I could illustrate an idea you because I want to call out because I
have the our the pc I can do cool stuff like have a ruler so maybe these lines are not as cools I one
of them to be outlook easily able to come in and rotate this I can come in and get my
lines super straight I can come in and do this all ya like it you
lag it's cool and of course the last thing this is the bottom if I don't do it
yom member back in grade school the first thing you learn is that whenever you have a heart you got
put the arrow that do that ok and now because this is
the pc yes app that person was excited about the heart I wrote that heart for
might made person so I'm not going to lose this white board because I have the
power-pc, you know, what to see up to have this for later I'll go ahead and tweeted
to-you so this way are have it you remember that we love ink what you guys think about that?
of course we don't want to get in a way so by actually go and lock my pc right now check this out
of a lot get that entire ink workspace is available above lock I can get right back to what I was doing
when it's time the rock-and-roll you grab your device to massive button your ready to go man
okay.
Now beyond all this cool stuff inking is actually a platform so
are really showcase now a couple things of how this extending great inking experiences in
the office of maps app that we have and then also in adobe so check this out of
the start with maps sometimes it's hard to actually explain something to somebody as far as
where does a map look at this I want to make cc I'll take my pen and make a little
dot right here what happens though that dot this is smart ink man it becomes a point of interest
as a registered point of interest if I want to go over here me somebody over you know, by this by the water
I make another dot now watch what happens I just draw a line connecting the dots and look what happens this ink is
smart enough to know those two points to know that distance and actually see what's happening there
ok and also you'll be seeing the up we can easily get directions but beyond that here's
mouse a hell if you basin noise if you play with a three-d section of this map before, yeah,
if you have not you've gotta check this out let's say I want to go for a hike and I found a really cool route is
to go do this now watch what happens this ink is going to be smart enough again to
dryer no that that's two-point-one miles watch this I can make a little place and say here's what we're going to
meats and then up here also maybe we're going to stop and do some lunch
okay and then right up here maybe I'm going to go and say here's we're going to
do a picture all right so the I make these custom routes these custom knows their
available across all my windows devices but watch what happens look at this when I
turn this the three-d that ink is smart enough to actually stick to that thing it knows
that a topographical map ballistic into it and watch this when I actually rotate this little billboards that I wrote
of smart enough to face me the entire time as the our of the pen and the
pc coming together how you feel about that?
I'm going to revisit some childhood trauma here my teachers marking red stuff
a papers consistently but check this out we've all
done whether helping your children with their homework or if you're a teacher yourself but look,
how you this is now in word across outward it's gone maybe I don't like this whole paragraph ok
we've always had inking word but watch how the text is actually reflowing now also if you're like
me not artistically inclined maybe when you highlight stuff it looks like this that's cool look what happens
yall app if you're like okay never write it yes you do a whole
paragraph now also today powerpoint as a great job at aligning things
naturally on vertical horizontal axes but check this out let me show you what the ruler can do here so,
two things when I move this really with two fingers I am easy and able to easily
control rotation what I use one that rotations locked
so what I can actually do is move this down here and snap these objects alongside this ruler
all right so this is easily coming together, yeah, can now when I line this up
check this out it's really easy for me to draw some who little diagonal lines to make
my slide look awesome that's the our of the pen and the pc coming together all right now
beyond office beyond maps we know the ink windows ink is a platform for everybody and adobe embracing this of to
talking do something they made for us check this out what you seeing right now it's going
to come up so it's very fake but that's a stencil called a french curve is willfully
fakes adobe does not want their tools to get the artist way all right but watch what happens simultaneous pen and
touches enabled with the windows ink platform look how that artist is easily able to use touch and
pen together to be able to actually make these perfect lines on the shoe with that french curve stencil I mean that's awesome
this is empowering new experiences the tech is not-guilty in the way
its enabling that is the goal what you're seeing here is an example of the amazing latency
or lack there of more of the windows ink platform the ink is flowing completely smoothly out of that pen
I mean you would never know that it's actually a device doing that because that's our goal how you guys feel about that?
Ladies and gentlemen that is just the beginning there is no way I could so you all this
onstage there's so much more common as a kind of give you a glimpse
into what we got going on there's a little sizzle video take a look.
That awesome moi.
All those experiences bryan just showed are built on our universal windows.
We designed this platform for all types of apps from productivity to
gaming.
Holographic we designed this platform for all types of devices
phones tablets the pcs iot seeds large screens like surface
hub and hololens or xbox and more.
And, we designed this platform for all of
our customers for all the needs of our commercial customers and for those of our developer
partners targeting consumers and this is an open platform.
For over thirty years windows as welcome
and open ecosystem of hardware partners software partners developer partners wherever they are
round-the-world and nothing changes with the universal windows platform the
universal windows platform brings together all of that windows history as well as
everything that today's users expect from a modern app platform
microsoft's seamless and robust install uninstall and seamless updates.
And, our two hundred seventy million users of windows
ten they visited the store over five billion times.
And, our universal windows platform developers have responded
the some incredible new apps a number of new developers is growing month over
month with the sixty percent growth in just the last few months alone.
These developers are bringing some incredible new apps to the store some
coming very soon so partners like twitter bank of america starbucks
hoover disney's squaring x yahoo worldwide wrestling and more.
And, facebook we
bringing a new universal app for facebook
instagram and messenger to the store very soon.
How very excited to share
that facebook will also be bringing their facebook audience network an app
install sdk to all of our universal windows platform developers
zthree million facebook advertisers can reach their customers
through your apps?
Now this is not just.
Momentum in the consumer space processing great adoption from
our commercial customers thousands of organizations are now piloting the use of the windows
store for business within their organization
in building incredible apps to take advantage of let's take a look at one partner was really leading away.
Boeing is the world's largest research company so,
majority the world are planks our commercial airline flight today or
boeing deformity triple seven came out to we thought that was a pretty data richer
blood the seventy-seven citibank behind machine produces thirty times as much data is
the troublesome and every succeeding generation will be even more.
As part of what boeing digital aviation we developed software
to provide operational efficiency for airline customers the electronic
flight bagged is essentially the workflow for pilots from
pre flight to post fly up until about three or four years ago pilots with terry thirty
forty pounds worth of paper or navigation charge there and router like
of developers shows windows ten because the flexibility of the platform
the release of transitioning onto it
and some opportunity to present content that we've not had.
Our future business is going to be more and more the accumulation of different
applications sober universal windows platform will help us to copilot
with real-time decision-making to our business is all about tarnishing that data coming off the airplane
So, you can do things with the universal windows
platform you just cannot do on any other platform.
And, this is a developer conference so I think it's about time we looked at some code.
Please welcome kevin gallo.
Good morning I'm so excited to be here.
We know that every innovation and step forward with
windows is only as powerful as the ecosystem that rallies
around.
That means not just building investments in
windows for customers but more importantly investing in windows
for you our developers and not just building windows apps either
but whether you're building your cloud services websites or even
apps rather platforms we want windows to be the place where you can be
the most productive and successful we want windows to be home.
For developers.
Let's start off with some of the newest innovations coming
to universal windows platform and how're enabling developers to
push the envelope with natural input and intuitive design.
So, here I have an application adult launch it here.
Now one great thing about native applications
is the ability to really harness the our of the gpu and build stunning and
one-point-eight differentiated user experiences for your apps.
We've added hardware-accelerated sixty frame per second
animation effects these effects bring richer and more immersive designs
that create a sense of depth layering
and fluidity which help make your apps more delightful and intuitive to use to
my app I've infinite just a few of these and I want to show you the first one here the blur effect as I
move my fingers I get this blur that is synchronized to my fingers in perfect harmony
here absolutely no glitches and just looks stunning its layered it's all in real time is
nothing faked up we also have the ability to do mouse-based effects here
is any kind of enemy effect and layer as I move my mouse I get these bars in this chart you can see
that as I over one I get this layering to get a great feel for
how, you know, the actual bar is there in the actual graphics here so when I showed
this summer designer can tell you how excited they were with these new gpu
that gpu effects and what they are able to go do it their designs now on
to move on to kind of my favorite which is windows ink and how we
want all deaths to be able to quickly and easily integrate ink
into their experiences and make the pen come alive for end-users so I'm
going show you is typical here at a conference the
hello world for windows ink going to start with the code?
I have my xaml so I built in xaml and I have two controls the first one here is
an canvas control we introduced this last year this is where I get
all my strokes and drawing all that capabilities all built into
the single control interesting new control its a stock control now built into the
sdk this is the ink toolbar you also bryan use this has the pen
the tips eraser and that ruler that we showed you and all
had to do was do a binding statement here from the actual toolbar to the canvas so
knows which canvas is acting on two lines of xaml that's all you have
to do me show you what I get for those two lines just, you know,
it's real so here I can just go start drawing right here on top of this chart it
can highlight something here and pointed out and I can also just pop up my ruler and
here can move the ruler and you're kind maybe trying to find have rhythm as good
bryan at this and segment address some lines here between it you see all of
that with just those two lines of just those two lines of xaml.
It's never been easier haired rich inking features to your apps
but of course we have a host of additional ink apis so you can
build some of the advanced experiences that bryan showed you so
this is just a few of the many features coming to the universal
platform this platform in total there over one thousand new apis
and features by now that the end of the day things only become real
for devs when you get your hands-on so I m excited to announce that today
we are releasing visual studio update to end.
A preview of the anniversary sdk.
Give them a spin and let us know what you think.
The next I want to move in talk about web development last year
we introduced hosted web apps this allows developers to easily bring
their web experiences to the windows store they can leverage your existing web investments
and at the same time get full access to native
capabilities like cortana bluetooth ink and more this is resonating with
our web community we've seen lots of highly rated web apps submitted to the windows store
including american express yahoo mail zulily and more.
However,
when we talk to develop web developers they still struggled with using
windows as their primary dev box as many of them have workflows which
rely land open source command line tools scripts and frameworks we're going to fix
set so windows can be your home
so today I m so excited to announce the bash shell?
coming to windows moi?
Real bash is coming to windows this is not
a vm this is not cross-compiled tools is native ubuntu
linux binaries running on windows to the magic of a new windows subsystem we
part with canonical to deliver this great consul experience which
you'll be able to download directly from the windows store inside a bash of
access the native file system vt one hundred support sh
and all of your favorite command line tools let's dive into tech can take a look.
So, here I have a website on ramming running the edge browser
is a ruby website that we built it's hosting a azure vienna linux vm in
azure and I can I also built a hosted web app with it so I
use launched app all had to do was take the earl create a name for it and
submit to windows store any produced an app ex me it downloads when the user downloads
the here so I haven't had anything extra to yet but I want to making this thing come alive and
do better some ahead of the ability to take is a banking app sites sci-tech the ability to use
the native camera and really get a great camera experience on the device like expect so I'm a
hop over here?
To bash.
So, here you see I do ls I can see my local system I'm going to move over
My c drive wholeness auto completion here.
Than I used first
former go modify my javascript just two parts my javascript comes down that lights and use
the windows functionality and then I need to change my ruby code on the back-end.
Of course my favorite enter is emax so.
Going to use emax but you can use all any of your favorites they're
all their survey can choose the one that they enjoy the most.
You see here my javascript that I do a idea of check here first this is how I make sure I can
share my code if I'm running inside of the application I just check see whether the windows is the
definitions there if it is and I have access to all the windows apis if not that I'm being hosted in the
browser add-on right of this code and you can see here I'm just coined
the standard rt apis that I get access to and I get
the native experience because they are the native app apis that
I'm actually calling someone the save that now I'm going to sh in to
my linux via and azure there.
To try to figure my password.
So, here.
What I'll do it again use emax modify this file?
So, you know, like on all these
demos I'm scan comment some code is just takes too long to actually go
modify it awesome uncommon that code in ruby it saved all I need to do is restart that
application so I get the latest version.
Solves pop over here launch it you might notice here it edit
a new menu item at my ui did so I can say scan check here
negatives native experience I got this check here from a giorgio for
a thousand dollars but, I'm really not can actually take a picture because last time it bounced
so obvious can exit out here and be done so you know,
with bash coming to windows bringing the
our of open source command line tools to windows.
What do you think?
For your samoa.
Website.
So, now when to ask how many people here have built
either a win thirty-two app or a dot net application.
For rights fake you for being a part of
our windows family in so today I m excited to announce that word's
now adding the desktop app converter four wintry to
in dot net action games with this converter does it takes
an existing desktop app and converted into a centennial what
we now call a modern desktop app developers can now take advantage
of the modern apps and games and submit them to the windows store.
With this conversion code continues to run with
very minimal changes in addition modern desktop apps
also have access to all universal apis when
running on windows ten let's see this samoa.
Here I am microsoft I m run the desktop app converter that takes
the existing installer in this case it's an msi but it can be a set of that
x you any installer out there and it's converting working with sage who
is initially there in accounting software convert their sage
two hundred application into a modern desktop app convertible produced
an app ex package that sage can take in submit to the windows store
just like any other universal application so what I'll do here is the apathetic
produce here's double click on and now we've added support for double click on top of
epics is to make it easy to install and debug locally guesstimate little delighter right there fight
select get live tiles and full integration of actually already installed from the store so you can see here in the
start menu my when thirty-two applicator stages wintry to application is now have
access to live tiles and show some the sell figures I can click it here and
launches the application minimize that you'll see it also able to
pasta toast bangor dismiss me show you this in visual studio what I had to go
do to do this so there is a single solution here I have
two projects the first is the win seven codess is just your standard wintry to code
here with no modifications so why modified it didn't have to it would
have just worked then I added this extra project which is the universal code that although
the live tiles so what happens is when sage loads
able to check this running on windows ten will loaded the ll and use the extra functionality
otherwise continues like it was and over here you see that boilerplate standard,
you know, a notification and live tile code that is just straight out universal windows code.
So, I'm also happy to share that sage
two hundred will be coming to the windows store this summer and
faucet for those of you ensues install shield or the which tool set
will work with both flexera and firegiant to produce modern app packages directly so
you don't even have to use the converter presents update you
said your project and they get both an app ex as well as your msi we're making
it easy for developers to bring more than sixteen million
when thirty-two indicted apps to the windows store finally.
We want windows to be your home not just for developing apps for windows but for developing
apps for all devices when I talk to developers hidden many of
you using architecture we have a shared common core
that you build native ui for each of the you urge the platforms that your targeting
in finally light up native capabilities with platform-specific apis for things
such as the camera notifications and commerce csharp developers they
still you can start with you wb to grow target the grow ever-growing base of windows
ten devices in now woods xamarin you can target ios
and android as well let me hop over visual studio and show you.
So, here we're looking at the code for the real microsoft health app which is
a companion app to the microsoft band you guys got bands out there absolutely awesome.
So, microsoft band users have windows android and ios
devices so the health team needs to have an app for all of them.
Udp app that they started with uses a xaml ui on top of
a csharp library containing the core business logic and
the service connectivity because the health app was designed this way it was easy
to use xamarin to take it to ios and android let me show you
here the project so at the bottom here is one of the price I have this
is the bulk of the code is all the shared code among all the different platforms
he's a huge amount of code you really is like I said this is the actual health application format
shown code and left side admonish here that a lot of you want to show sometimes a real code?
Notes pretty easy one and, now have a word a projects reach the
heads one for universal apps they started with anyone for ios and one for android
the nice thing is with xamarin you can not only debug
emulator for windows we now also have the ability to do the inner-loop to cycle
development for their android head have the android emulator here that you can go run and
the windows and later as well in addition for ios developers we've also
had the ability to have a remote designer so you stay in visual studio
your entire time who loves staying in visual studio the entire
time I here is going to remote designer the
tweet their ui you tweak if ios as well.
windows can now be your home for developing apps for all devices
now before I go I want to personally thank you our developers
have taken the time to give us feedback into part with us
building great platform together
keep the feedback coming we cannot build the platform without,
you know, back to terry.
With this anniversary update we really been focused on making windows
ten-best home for all of your.
Enabling you to choose whatever shell you
want when powershell dos.
Or more coming soon.
Enabling you to embrace new device capabilities like
windows allow windows ink enabling you to take your existing dot
net winter into applications and distribute them
and through the windows store and enhance them with
all the new device capabilities we've been talking about.
Enabling you to
build new dot net code bases and take them cross platform and of course if
you're working for the highest performance precision laptop and
tablet to do all of your development on we have surface
There really has been no better time to be a windows developer.
Now with this anniversary update we have experiences that go beyond the
pc let's take gaming you want to go beyond your mobile devices into
your living room you taking advantage of the game consul you have
their your xbox one or hololens is the
world's first fully untethered holographic computer.
In the last few years.
Hololens has gone from a dream.
To a prototype.
now today we get to see what real customers are doing with it every day.
Please welcome phil spencer discuss gaming and
then alex kipman will join us to discuss holographic computing.
What's more
sports sixty-eight text is the first step in the forts a franchise moving to windows ten bits of
focused experience that brings the best of what motorsport has to offer to nuclear on the pc.
Moi text is actually
approve point of what first party can do with european directx twelve the
universal windows platform were able to drive it four-k and sixty frames a
second the highest fidelity we've ever deliver the universal aspect that's a real
true promise for us is the ability to radar code one store still going to
taylor that experiences that it's the best thing you can get on xbox the best thing you can get on
pcs but what it means it's reduce the development time for us and I really
surfaces not only in the code that we ripe but also the tool
said that we get to use and that's the thing that's going to grow the most over time moi
was a first-party is to make sure that platform that everyone's running on is the best one that they can
offer games on moving forward all of our date you're going to be shipping on windows
tend xbox.
Universal windows platform is great for the game
developers and gamers alike it's going to become even more powerful as a way of delivering amazing
experience across all of devices and windows ecosystem.
Hello, everyone good-morning I'm phil spencer I'm
proud to represent to be here my very first build conference to
represent the talented and creative teams responsible for gaming at microsoft.
You've heard this morning about how windows is the best platform
for developers today we'll spend time talking about how windows is the
bled best platform for the vast community of game developers
the universal windows platform provides developers the ability to
righty game and deployed across all windows ten devices from desktop
tablets and phones and xbox one this morning.
Thank you this morning we will demonstrate how windows ten provides
the most productive and efficient platform for developers
of all sizes because windows is and will continue to be
an open development ecosystem where anyone can build
deploy sell and service their games in applications?
And, the opening video we got to hear directly from one of our first-party studios
turn ten on the impact of the universal windows platform hat on bringing
forza motorsport six apex to windows ten and how uw
p can benefit both developers and gamers alike?
Through the universal windows platform our plan
its delivered games that will run better on
windows with more predictable performance more robust install uninstall
and servicing capability through a modern application platform.
And, greater safety for users through a protected runtime environment
and distribution of modern desktop applications on any store
including the windows store and via any development that deployment mechanism.
We recently launched three blockbuster franchises in
the windows store rise of the tomb raider gears of war ultimate edition
and just yesterday killer instinct season three.
And, I'm looking forward to the upcoming launch of quantum break next week.
We have heard the feedback from the pc gaming community loud and clear and we're
working to ensure windows ten has a great game experience
we will be enabling the ability to disable v-sync and adding support for
g-sync and freesync in may directx twelve added support for new
multiple gpu scenarios which work today for both windows thirty-two
can-you wa games.
And, we're committed to ensuring we meet or exceed the performance
expectations of full-screen games as well as the additional features
requested including support for overlays modding and more.
We also know many of you have
win thirty-two game code bases today and we want to give you access the
ability to easily package your games as modern desktop applications
through the desktop app converter let's take a look and see how that works.
So, one of my favorite games and I hear it's a
favorite of our founder a is age of empires so
what we did is we took age of empires to ht you can see append
the start menu that this is the package you would get from steam where it's available today and in
fact if you watch you'll see the live tile turn and you'll see the number of people that are
actually playing this game live right now and steamworks we have five thousand two hundred and twenty
three players so what we did is we took the package from steam ran it through the converter and turn it
on modern desktop application so let's launch it to see how it runs you can see
it launch our splash screen.
Steamworks kicks up.
Adhered it's so we're now in age to running just as
would run if you bought it from steam today multiplayer is here one of the
requests we've heard from people support for mods and how that's going to work stuff, you know,
anything about age too, you know, and, steam workshop we have the mod here's the list
of mods that are available for each to I could select any of these apply am
against the running when the running version of the game here and they would work just fine but I want to
actually boot the game?
And, just show use proof is here.
And, there you go so age do eights d running as a modern desktop
application taking advantage of all the features that windows stands enables on
while I love age to quava we want to challenge ourselves a little more to see how our
platforms holding up so we did an experiment in this is just the
experiment with our friends at cd projekt red we took the witcher occurring but for
many people as a twenty fifteen pc game of the year an amazing game ran it through
the same converter let me show you how it works so here is find the start menu.
It's bigger game takes a bit longer load.
It is so what you'll see a moi.
Is there it is the witcher to running a full frame rate as a modern desktop application?
This allows these games
to take advantage of the common services and technology and both xbox
in windows tent things like platform-specific features like live tile support
notifications like you just saw in this demo and kevin's demo earlier we
have consistent input support with controller and mouse and keyboard across all
of our devices and distribution in the windows store or any other store.
We've said from the start we want xbox one to be a great place for games
and also a great place for developers of all sizes so you can create new games
and application experiences today I
am pleased to announce xbox dev mode giving developers the
ability to convert their retail xbox one into a development kit.
Please welcome axes biker from our xbox platform team to show us how
thanks ashley we are building a truly universal platform where your apps run everywhere
including the xbox one which provides a huge opportunity for app developers to bring
their experiences to life in the living room so now I'm going to show you how anyone can take
a retail xbox one and turn it into a dev kit.
I was playing forts over here but I really want to do is work on my app ash photo which I'll show
you in a minute but first I need to put my consul into dev mode.
So, go over here
now run the dev mode activation app which I've already downloaded from the store.
This app allows you to register your consul as a deb consul which I've already done using my
same account in dead-center where I submit all my other uw
p applications this means that I can switch to dev mode with a single button press.
Once the xbox is finished rebooting it will be in dev mode which means I can
deploy and debug my app now while attributing let's go over here to
the pc and look at asch photo running on the pc where I'm actually writing.
So, you can see how the ui elements move and adjust as a change the size of
the window and now let's see how we can deploy this theme app to the xbox one
so I'll stop debugging over here on the pc and I'll switch
local machine to remote machine this is the ip address of my xbox.
And, then the signal.
And, since I've already paired visual studio with my xbox I can do a remote deploy just like
any other universal windows device.
Right so that's my consul in years my app running on my xbox one so,
this is the exact same code that we were just debugging over here but now that
it's on the consul you can tell that it's been optimized for the living room.
Good news is that the universal windows platform did a lot of the heavy lifting,
for example, the controller just works
all xaml controls have already been optimized to work with the game bad just like you would
expect including focus navigation and not just on xbox.
Works the same way and the desktop when you have a controller plugged in fact all
the xaml controls are designed to work great with touch mouse and controller.
Helpful life.
It also means that
you can continue to test when you don't have your xbox look in your flight back home.
Now since this is a universal windows application it also have access to the same
universal apis including apis for speech recognition and synthesis so
I've added a fun feature which allows me to add speech bubbles to my photos I can simply use
the speech recognizer to fill them in which an xbox is way
easier than typing so let me show you how this works will caption this photo right now.
Lions bark right.
Boom there we go.
So, much easier than typing.
Ok, I want to show you guys one more thing so in addition to the
dev mode activation app I showed earlier there's another app
called dev home which will automatically get loaded on your consul once you've put it in dev mode.
And, when you run it has everything you need is a developer from anything from account management to
developer settings most importantly once I'm done working on my app
for the night and I want to go back to playing forza I can just go ahead and
press leave developer mode and back to retail mode?
I should mention that a preview of dev mode will be available starting today.
Thanks ashley.
Our commitment to turn every xbox one into a dev kit
is into hobby gets a commitment
it's a commitment to empower every developer on the planet to reach the
largest addressable tv audience on one open app platform.
But, enabling developers to create and deploy uw key apps and games on xbox one is
just the beginning with the upcoming windows ten anniversary update we will
continue our progress that brought xbox live to all windows devices
and the xbox app to windows ten where millions of gamers are connected
around the world we will also be adding a single unify store
across devices giving developers new features and consumers
a consistent experience new support will be will include features
that game developers have come to expect and require from xbox one into the
windows store including support for bundles season passes preorders and
more we will also be bringing cortana to xbox one
cortana will become your personal gaming assistant would help to help you find
great new games new challenges or help you with tips and tricks.
And, the foundation for some of the most-requested new features,
features like background music which will also come with the anniversary update.
Will announce new anniversary update features for xbox one and windows ten at you
three in june?
Fate finally I want to close with the technology
that allows developers to maximize their own investment across xbox one and windows
ten directx twelve allows developers
to unlock the full potential of the graphics hardware in pcs in
xbox one it's the most powerful in efficient graphics api we've ever
shipped we're seeing incredible industry adoption of directx twelve in fact it's
the fastest adoption of any directx version in history.
Let's take a look at what that our can
deliver when put in the hands of the greatest developers on the planet thank you.
Good morning everyone wow what a phenomenal
time to be a windows developer guys realize that from xbox.
To holograms windows and our universal platform is
where this future is being created a future
that is impossible on any other platform or set of devices last
year here at build we ask you to share in our dreams for
a holographic tomorrow a future where we bring three-d
holographic content into the real world enhancing the way we
experience life beyond our ordinary range of perception.
And, today is the day
where we leap from dreaming about mixed worlds.
To having microsoft hololens become
a reality exclusively on windows stent and to help.
Thank you.
And, to help us celebrate this moment mets help me welcome
on stage hololens is co-creator kudo tsunoda.
Hey, kudo.
World waded to announce and we couldn't be more proud that today
march thirtieth twenty sixteen microsoft hololens the
first and still the only untethered holographic computer
will start shipping to our windows developers and to our enterprise partners
our journey starts right here right now with
all of you our creators our dreamers our windows
developers.
Should moi?
I have waited for this moment for a very long-time.
And, because hololens is a windows stand
device all of our tools are familiar your investment in uw
piece will continue to carry forward but to help a little bit
with inspiration let me update you on a project that we launched earlier
this year called share your idea the community submitted
ideas for applications that we could build all of you voted
and we built.
We built galaxy explorer in just a short six weeks
we chronicled the project all along the way this week we
finish the project and today we are announcing
the project is going to go up on the windows store and all of the
code will be made available online via github let's take a quick look.
With hololens dev kit about to go out into the world we ask the community what would you want
us to build after so many more than five thousand ideas you voted for
a galaxy explorer we've invaded you into the process of brainstorming
prototyping and developing for hololens galaxy explorer is a jumping off point
for developing for hololens so you can actually download all of our source code and see how we inc
gaze gesture voice spatial sound and spatial mapping and then use that directly in
your own projects we want to show you how we actually develop apps through videos and blog
post we let-you into our development process we also brought in the share your idea
contributor take a look at galaxy explorer and give us feedback
from the seems like there's so many possibilities gather building apps I want to push
create boundaries in samoa.
There's still so much more you can have to be app now we want to see what ideas you
can today were they seem to have asked.
The source code you can use it is inspiration ceremonies.
Samoa.
From individual developers
to customers like volvo autodesk and trimble.
Thousands of people have
experience hololens over the last year.
Dreaming about holographic experiences
that eventually become pilots and ultimately
become real experiences deployed in production the change the
way we work communicate learn and play technical buildings as an example
they are rethinking the entire construction planning process
from first pitch through groundbreaking development or
take japan airlines on the other hand they have a vision for holographic computing
the impact every area of
their training and operations now these are just two examples of companies
and organizations of all shapes and sizes across a wide
range of industries who are piloting amazing universal
windows applications created specifically for mixed reality
in our new holographic landscape but pilots.
And, proof of concepts eventually move into production last year
here at build professor mark griswold join me on stage.
In we showed you a proof of concept where we use hololens to innovate
on how medical students learn.
At the same time case western reserve university and the cleveland
clinic broke ground the construction of their brand-new medical school
facility an amazing facility that
will use hololens as a key part of their curriculum now over the last two
months twelve months this proof of concept has moved into production and
today I am honored to have doctor pamela davis
dean of case western reserve university school of medicine into
our team members henry and jeff join us to tell us more
about teaching medicine with hololens welcome.
Doctor david moi.
Good morning.
At case western reserve our motto is think beyond the
possible.
And, today we and the cleveland clinic are constructing
a state-of-the-future health education campus.
Within this building our students will learn using the
most forward use looking educational programs hololens
is a key part of this now last year we showed a few things that we thought
might be possible with hololens.
Since october we've had a small team of three
computer programmers turning our ideas into reality.
Today we're going to show you some of our work
on our holographic anatomy program an example of the
hours of curricular content that we have created now anatomy is all about
mastering the complex systems in the body and you can see from the digestive
system here that there are a lot of parts in a small space.
And, students need to understand not only how these parts fit together but how
they work together henry can you tell us which organ in the body
aids in digestion and also makes insulin yes the
be the pancreas to be a little hard to see it behind the stomach here
but thankfully with hololens it's really easy to get the best view of things.
Now another area that's difficult for our students to fully grasp is the nervous
system.
Hololens can make this much easier by improving
our interactive learning beyond the single classroom.
Professor mark griswold can teach us about the anatomy of
the brain even though he's in cleveland let's show you how this works.
Are you there mark?
hi pam my everybody welcome to our new classroom.
This is our new system that allows me to teach and interact with you even though I'm not there
at build I'll tell you this feels really natural the three of us can see each
other's were talking which makes us feel connected and even though you can only see my
head and hand you get a sense of my body language this is
really changing what it means to be in class mark let show them the white matter
tracks these tracts act like super highways allowing
messages to travel from one part of the brain to another this example comes from
an mri scan of a real patient from the laboratory of professor
cameron mcintyre at case western reserve university it's
critical that our students know how these structures relate to one another I can tell you
I've looked at datasets like this for over ten years and I never fully understood
their three-d structure until I saw them in hololens let's say we have a patient with a brain
tumor which are showing here with this red area hey jeff and henry.
Can you see how this tumor intersects the light blue tract but not the green tract or
the yellow one this allows us to predict the impact to this tumor on the
patience symptoms and their outcomes after surgery?
This could impact the occipital lobe back here.
Which may harm the patient's vision might also influence the
prior lobe here which would affect their sense of touch?
The quicker our students learn facts like
teas the more time they have to
think with them we're teaching them to think like a doctor.
Thanks mark for joining us today.
Bye everybody.
Being untethered able to walk around three-d holographic content
gives our students a real advantage students of commented that a fifteen-minute
session with hololens could have saved them dozens of hours in the
cap cadaveric lab
when we have only four short years to train them this is extremely valuable.
We're so grateful to microsoft for giving us the opportunity to
develop this technology and we can't wait to collaborate with others.
Using
hololens to think and to see beyond the possible.
Just amazing thank you so much.
Thank you so much.
Now nasa was
our first partner they have also made incredible progress over
the last year they have developed several applications
that are already deployed in production let's take a quick look.
Nasa were excited to apply mixed-reality technologies to the challenges we're facing
in space exploration collaboration with microsoft for building
applications support engineers responsible for the design assembly spacecraft
action of working on the international space station and scientists are now using our mars
to onsite in mission operations onsite to powerful tony truck scientists and
engineers portable nods but because we always felt it should remain
only within transfer taken the core on-site
amazed, amazed experience that allows the public puts fool threat.
We call this new experiences destination moi.
Mars can be a lonely place so we've created holographic captures of an astronaut
in a member of the curiosity rover team to be on guides on this journey this
game is an opportunity to immortalized a hero moi bozo.
Looking forward to opening the destination mars exhibit at the kennedy space center visitor complex
and summer twenty-six team we can't wait to share this journey with the world
Samoa.
And, here's the best part.
Of thank you.
And, use my favorite part nasa brought destination mars
your to the build conference so that all of
you our windows developers can be the first people in the world to
view mars from the same perspective as nasa scientists working today.
Hololens star shipping today.
Marks.
Thank you.
Marking another great step on our journey of interacting with
computers
ever more-personal ways my ask of all of you.
To actually join us and help us create.
This new reality our partners have done exactly
that over the last twelve months and the progress is nothing
short of spectacular so let me leave you today with a snapshot of
their tremendous creativity I hope to see all of you this week your at build thank you.
It fantastic to see the progress on the windows platform and one of the things that
I'm most excited about is how windows can become
the dev box of choice whether you're writing wintry to apps and converting them
into modern desktop apps writing universal windows apps web
apps or even linux backends or
ios android apps you can do them all right on windows and its
fantastic to see bringing that developer love to built.
also are really excited about I think the opportunities the new frontiers.
That windows represents for all of you as developers whether it be
writing that next pen app whether it's the speech app
its computer vision all holograms these new frontiers I think are
a fantastic opportunity where you can learn a lot about them at build and we really hope to
see your creation in our store so what
are now switch gears to talk about this conversation as a platform.
As I said this is at the confluence of all of
our three platforms azure office three-six five as well as windows stand.
It is in fact,
you know, best brought a whole with an anecdote.
That she knew shared with me about is mall.
Yahoo's eighty-years-old lives in china she has been try to use because of
cheese influence computers and she found it very hard even the
web although it was one of the greatest democratizing forces of computing she found
it hard to navigate between websites was uncomfortable clicking on
lengths the mobile phone and the app revolution ob
further democratized things but even there going and finding the right app
was difficult so she never got around using it was using sms and
now with wechat she's able to at the age of eighty not
only have all the conversations with people seamlessly but
she's also able to interact with businesses and
And, that shows the our.
Of human language.
We want to take that our of human language and as I said earlier
apply it more pervasively to all of the computing interface and
the computing interaction and to do that though you have to infuse.
Into computers and computing around us intelligence that means you
have to bring forth these technologies of artificial intelligence and machine
learning so that we can teach computers to learn.
Human language have conversational understanding teach them about
the broad context people places things.
Context about your preferences your personal knowledge.
So, that they can really help you with your everyday tasks
and everyday life both at work and elsewhere.
So, as we infuse.
Intelligence
into everything I think it's very important to have a principled approach.
a way to guide our design as well as how we build things?
So, at microsoft we are focused on an approach that grounded in our
mission to empower people and organizations all over the planet to achieve model
the three core principles here first we want to build
intelligence that augments human abilities and
experiences ultimately it's not going to be about man versus machine
is going to be about man with machines each of us
excel a very different things.
The fact that we have creativity empathy emotion.
And, judgment.
That can then be mixed with fast computation the ability to reason over large amounts of
data and do pattern recognition fast it's that bringing together
that I think is going to help us move our society forward?
We also have to build trust right into our technology that means.
You have to have technology that has built-in protections for privacy
east got transparency you have security as well as compliance.
And, lastly.
All technology that we build to be more inclusive and respectful
we need to build technology so that more people can use technology.
And, we want
to build technology such that it gets the best of humanity not the worst.
this is already guiding us as we build skype translate.
To have conversational understanding as we build out cortana to have
more expertise as we build hololens to have environmental understanding.
Reuse this approach when we get it wrong in fact just last week when we
launched our incubation tay which is a social bot in the united states
we quickly realized that it was not up to this mark.
So, we're back to the drawing board.
Why we continue to incubate xiaoice and rina in
china and japan and learn why is it that the social bots there'd work differently?
And, that's how we want to make progress this approach is always going to be
front-and-center to us.
When we talk about conversations as a platform
that reactors there's baths people?
We want to be able to have the most natural conversations with other
people.
We want in fact to enrich our
conversations and skype translate is a fantastic example of that because I'm able to
talking to different languages and really have automatic translation
we also have presence you saw in the holographic
demo how you can have remote presence.
These are all ways for us to enhance human conversations.
But, we want to take that same our of human conversations and applied to everything
And, that's where these other actors come in a personal digital
assistant that knows you knows about your world is always with you
across all your devices helping you with your everyday tasks.
And, bots are like new applications that you converse with
you're not really looking for multiple applications.
Pages and pages a websites or apps but you just able
to call on any application as a bot right within a conversational canvas.
So, this is the rich world of conversations that we envision people-to-people
people to your personal digital assistant people-to-bots and
even personal digital assistants calling on bots on your behalf.
That's the world that you're going to get to see in the years to come.
So, you can conceptualize this platform.
Where human language?
Is the new ui layer?
Bots are like new applications.
And, digital assistants are meta apps for like the new browsers.
And, intelligence is infused into all of your interactions
that's the rich platform that we have.
So, let's start.
By talking about cortana.
We introduced cortana two years ago and
ever since then it's becoming smarter every day.
Because of its ability to know you.
To know about your organization to know about the world
and reason about all of this on a continuous basis.
It's built natively into windows.
But, it's not limited to windows
it's going to be available on all your devices
whether ios android across all of your applications.
Because if it's going to be a useful personal digital assistant it has to be about
new not a single device and that's really
how we are building out cortana.
And, we're also making it such that the expertise of cortana is
extensible it's truly unbounded in that way so the opportunity
for developers to addicts their expertise the expertise that they have
in their applications this services into cortana
so that can further drive engagement for their applications
and services that developer opportunity is something that we want to talk about so to show
you how this unbounded personal digital assistant works across
all of your devices and creates this ability for developers to
extended with your expertise please help me welcome markets ash from the cortana team.
Good morning everyone it's great to be here at build to get a chance to give you an early preview of
our future plans first I want to talk about a new experience the anniversary update
we want windows to be the best place to have a voice conversation with cortana, cortana
is answering one million voice questions per day we have almost a thousand applications that
integrate with cortana voice commands and today there's a new cortana app store collection
available so customers can check out some great examples we want to go even further and
make a voice conversation with cortana as easy as a voice conversation with a human.
So, I've got this beautiful all-in-one with a nice big-screen you can see at the top left
corner cortana is ready for me to have a conversation I go sausalito tonight I don't know where that
is I don't know-how long it's going to take cortana can help me event hey cortana.
How long would take to get to sausalito?
It will take twenty-seven minutes to drive to sausalito it's about twelve miles
away all the things you expect to work in this experience on the lock screen I can play my
music I can set alarm and this also gives a much bigger stage to let cortana
is personality shine through.
Hey, cortana will tell me a science joke.
Sodium, sodium, sodium, sodium, sodium, sodium, sodium, sodium batman.
Vanna on nana old school batman, batman you guys with me.
This experience is going to be shipping in
the anniversary update it's also going to be available in thirteen countries.
Cortana is going to be here all week and the expo fair please go checker out but now I want to show you how
she helps me get stuff done here's an early preview of some new experiences that will release the coming months.
Notice that cortana is coming to outlook and
scheduled some appointments for me it's the blue with the circle.
The idea there is cortana is now in outlook and
she looking at my email and my calendar with my permission and
helping me get things done stay on top of things a good example this week I was exchanging a bunch of
email with our microsoft travel service trying to figure out the best time to get home on friday
cortana is able to understand that conversation about me doing anything adding
create appointment she automatically put all that flight information my counter to make it really easy for me to track.
She applies the same conversational intelligence to help me stay on top of commitments
in email I get a ton of email which makes it easy for me to forget things I said
I would do so here cortana is flagged something I said
semi manager today I was actually going to get ahead of this on the plane but the siren song of
that flight infotainment system gap me again no problem cortana is there and she
knows the last time I made an update she knows where the document as I can ask a good take care of this warming.
Send chuck the powerpoint that are worked on last night.
Sure, thing I found this powerpoint document is this it.
I go ahead and get that sent.
Since cortana is not bound to specific device thank you thank you.
Now since cortana is not bound to a specific device she helps me keep track of notifications that are
happening right here my android phone while I'm doing work on my pc.
So, here I've got a notification a text message that came in from my friend ben he's here in the bay area
what's michigan together go blue and we were talking about
get-together after the keynote any michigan grads out there we go for.
I can go ahead and respond right here for my pc.
Cortana knows that I'm talking about meeting with ben she offers to add
this to my calendar.
And, then she tells me got a couple of other things there can I help you movies.
But, see then are some work-related stuff I choose ben and what she did
there is appointments from noon on wednesday
automatically shift to the appointment the free block of time I have there on thursday?
Now since that meeting with ben is over lunch you can see here the cortana is brought
in some proactive actions that she thinks can help me cortana has a team of experts
that she relies on this idea that cortana doesn't need to know everything she can go and ask experts
for health experts are all of you developers that are creating these amazing apps and services that can integrate
right into cortana so the cases this meetings over lunch I might want to book a table
we might not have time so I might need to bring in some food or she can offer some helpful
suggestions about things to do here you can see a bunch of options city food tour sounds great
here some information about that notice the option to buy tickets.
Extensibility also means help me get that action done here create a very simple sample application
city food tour notice cortana is passed in some context for me there are two of us in the meeting
invite here some other information I can confirm my order now I've got tickets purchased.
This same experience also works for business applications so the next time I go to cortana
she's queuing up another thing she thinks I might want to work on in this case I took a taxi
last night and cortana found out there was a receipt my email and she's
offered to help me put that into my expense report we use the microsoft expense
application internally to track this kind of thing when I click on that notice that all of the
information and details map receipt are put into that application.
And, I go ahead and add choose to save that.
Since cortana is not bound to a particular device I can finish all these tasks here
on my android phone.
So, when I go ahead launch cortana?
You can see that my meeting with ben is here and I got the tickets to the food city
tours the microsoft expense application here I go ahead and choose to submit that
and it's all taken care of since the phone as my most personal device
its with me all the time cortana can augment me in very interesting ways so I
have a five-year-old son and I started this tradition two years ago when I
brought him home a toy from a business trip.
Now every time daddy goes in a business trip little man thinks
is birthday and daddy better deliver and bring home yet another toy I
don't remember the name of the toy store that I went to last year was here but it
had great transformers and things that he wants so since cortana is with me she can help enhance my memory.
What toy store did I go to last year at build?
You can see she finds the correct toy store again she brings in helpful proactive actions.
Now let me show you how easy it is to create these actions.
Here on the developer portal today we're announcing an invite-based preview
for proactive actions and here's the portal that you can use to connect your apps and websites to cortana.
I want
to share two examples of partners that are already integrated glimpse and just the.
Glimpse provides an easy way to safely share your location with some and real-time
data great idea for improving the arm running late experience beatings.
Instead of fumbling around trying to figure out how to send a text message and figure out what am I going to
get there and I really going to get there at the time I think I can just send a glimpse which gives
all the attendees real-time tracking of me with a map and tells me my expected eta.
Just eat is a leading food delivery service based uk and they're very excited about scenarios like helping you
order dinner when you're working late let me show you how easy it was for just eat to configure the portal
only a few steps the first thing you do is you go and add insights,
insights control when cortana surfaces your action.
That's this column right here this column is the contextual info this is the information that you want
your app to request from customers so that just eat example just eat would like to know
my cuisine preferences because they can do a much better job of give-me helpful suggestions if they knew that I love sushi.
Customers are always in control of data that cortana shares so she's always going
to ask permission before any data sent applications and services.
Here the deep links that you create open your app these deep links are
not restricted to a particular device a platform we support windows applications we
support android applications ios applications are coming in the future and we also support websites.
And, then finally some metadata that you ads that shows how the experience shows up
in the cortana ui along with an icon.
So, here you can see a sample appointment and both glimpse and just eat
are here as actions it only take took just
eat fifteen minutes to get their app registered to work in this experience.
We're looking forward to seeing all the great ideas you have for integrating with cortana please request
an invites the cortana developer preview and I hope to see you at the cortana sessions thank you.
Thanks mark is that gives you a glimpse
of how cortana is a truly unbounded personal assistant that's always
with you and for developers it represents a new opportunity for
you for you to be able to take the
expertise that you have in your applications the intelligence that you have in your
services and then register them as extensions and insights and action.
So, we want to now move to another
canvas another set of tools where conversations are taking place these
are our communications tools there are a wide variety of their in fact we
envision a world where there are going to be in more and more communications
tools because that's one of the most innate things that we as people do.
And, we want all of these conversational
tools to become rich canvases for computation.
In our case we have outlook and skype.
And, we want to ton bs into these rich conversational canvases
skype has over three hundred
million connected users each month every day there
is over three billion minutes of.
Voice calls happening on skype so
it's a tremendous amount of activity so now
imagine if we can open up skype.
Not only to have all the rich people-to-people
conversations things that we are doing with skype translate or
skype on the hololens what if we can now.
Bring in.
Your personal digital assistant right to your conversational
canvas what if we brought the world a bots.
The new applications to be able to do anything.
Like hire cab.
Book a ticket anything that you may want to do that you've done historically with
applications and websites now with bots right from within skype.
We don't even stop there.
You want to add richness
to these bots so it's not just text bots.
We want to have animation you want to have videos and we also want
to have holograms and to show you this rich world of conversational
canvases starting with skype I want to invite up on stage lilian from the skype the lilian.
Right hello everyone
I'm super excited to be here with you today I get the pleasure of showing
you our vision for how we see intelligence integrated into one of the
most popular ways that people communicate today skype.
Estate that, you know, and,
love is going to be smarter more helpful and entertaining.
We're moving into a world where you will soon be able to plan trips shop.
Even talk to intelligent bots all from within your skype chat.
I'm going to show you a demo of this next generation of skype scented scape will work
on ios android mac web you name it and I m going to show it to you on my windows phone.
So, here I see that I have one missed notification let's see that's from.
And, odds from gurdeep for those of you that don't know
greedy start corporate vice president for skates I canning are this as so
let's go into it and you see I have a visual video mail from somebody I'm going to play it.
Hey, I just learned you with
us keynote codess again this year congratulations attacks everything universe skype.
That is amazing I am a huge fan of code osman a send him a quick thank you.
So, right away as you're seeing here
there are some new things in this next generation of skype you see this visual video mail so
we have a video message with the transcript right below this is one of the examples where
we taking intelligence from things like skype translator and bringing them directly into everyday features
like video messages and narrative is telling me the team has sent me a little something
so that's really nice I'll send him a quick little happy emoticon so in this next generation of
said the other thing that you'll notice in the canvas is my personal assistant cortana
is always there in the upper right-hand corner cortana is there if I want to talk
to her one-on-one or in a group or even as you can see here she subtly
improving my messages by highlighting key points in my text like codess.
So, I can tap on codess you see this rich card powered by bing that showing us
set code is a real organization that microsoft
sponsors to really promote women in technology which is something that I'm very passionate about.
So, now you see cortana is actually sending me a private message I'm going to tap that and I
go into the one-on-one conversation I have with cortana so she's telling me the
custom cakes bot would like to know my location for delivery and yes I'll share it.
And, what I like to track delivery also yes I'll share it so right away what you're seeing here is that?
The agent cortana
is actually brokering the conversation with the third-party bot the custom cakes bot
now I see this rich card that is showing me that the cupcake is on its way and that
it will be here within a few minutes all of this is happening within my skype chats.
This is just one example of the many ways that you're going to
start seeing businesses using the our of skype and cortana to interact with their customers.
Now since I'm already talking to cortana and
I've committed to doing this keynote I'm going-to go ahead and try to plan the rest of my trip.
Please block my calendar for codess from april ten through april twelfth.
These other used push talk because I didn't feel like typing.
And, reilly everything your notice here is that cortana
actually has context for my previous chat with gurdeep so even though I just told that the
date it actually knows the location and, you know, that its from the conversation with gurdeep.
Now cortana is proactively thinking about the next steps in coordinating my trip so
she's actually suggesting that I connect with the westin bot anybody that knows me knows I normally stay at
a westin bot and I'm so you see here now is cortana has actually
introduced the westin bot into the conversation but not only has
he done that she has given the westin bot
context so I don't have to repeat myself the westin bot knows this is for dublin and
its for those particular dates all of this saves me a lot of time and effort.
Now there are suggested rooms I'm going to choose the normal room.
Confirmation and just like that into simple steps I was able to
block my calendar and also book my hotel room.
Now there's nothing else the westin bot can do for me so I m going to say no thank you.
And, now because cortana has all my relevant details the westin bot can actually leave the
conversation.
Now we're seeing a third aspect of cortana she knows my
connections she knows who I communicate with
so here you're seeing her actually suggest that when I go on this trip to dublin that I communicate with
my friend jani and I see this card I could call her directly from here
are video call her but I don't know what time it is so I'm going to choose to message her clicking that
takes me to the conversation I have with jani the other thing you'll notice is that cortana because she has
context about why I m pinging jani she's prepopulated the text
with context around when I'm going to dublin and basically why I want to talk to her.
And, fantastic jani is available and she's even going to show me around tab.
So, this is just a glimpse into how skype and cortana
powered by bing can make our conversations more productive informed and fine.
Now as you now real-time video is a big part of how skype is used today
I just showed you intelligence applied to messaging conversations and I now have the
pleasure of announcing we will also be bringing intelligence into real-time video.
Skype video baths will reinvent the way that friends family
and businesses get together for the first-time we will enable a very personalized
experience for you to connect with your favorite character business or
And, the best part is that starting today
developers will have access to our first ever skype bot sdk.
And, as you can see there you can also sign up to one of our global hackathons we're starting with the first one in
may which is happening here down in silicon valley and you'll be able
to seamlessly integrate into chats like I showed you or even
invent totally new audio and video experiences for an audience of millions.
to make this even sweeter for developers as of today skype consumers will
have access to bots in our latest windows ios and android apps.
But, this is just the beginning with hololens becoming available we
are also bringing intelligence into your virtual conversations
with skype for hololens please roll video.
Now the new seen what these rich conversational canvases as well
as personal digital assistants can do for you.
developers we think that this represents a huge opportunity for you
to write new types of applications we want
to empower all developers to do this new work that
means we want every developer to build.
Experts for cortana.
We want every developer to be able to build.
Bots as the new applications for every business
and every service we want all developers to be able
to infuse intelligence into their applications.
to really make this possible we think of a new run-time.
Which is this intelligence run time?
That's all coming together as part of cortana intelligence suite.
The runs on azure.
That's going to have a rich bot
framework a bot framework that will allow you to build.
Rich dialogue capability into your application into your bot.
A bot framework that will allow you not just to build bots for any one
canvas
we don't envision such a world we envision a world of many conversational canvas.
So, you will be able to take the bot framework and in fact integrate with all of
slack skype line outlook all of the canvases.
We also want to give you a set of micro
services these cognitive services so that you can have language understanding
speech understanding computer vision built into your applications and
also rich machine learning capability because we think
of this intelligence run time and cortana intelligence
suite is going to be core just like how the dot net run times were.
To all the applications that you're going to build going forward.
And, to give you a glimpse of this world and what cortana intelligence suite
can enable warning white up onstage my colleague dan lili as well
as cornelia to give you a sense for what development looks like with these new set of tools
and micro services dan first new thanks satya?
In today's demos of windows cortana and skype we've shown you how
microsoft is creating new conversational experiences if
you're developer or business professional you may want to add
bots and conversations your own products and we want to share our services and open
source our tools so you can use them to build your own great bots.
So, today I m so excited to introduce a brand-new
platform for creating intelligent and connected bots the microsoft bot framework.
What are you're building a simple tick-tack-toe bot creating a productivity bot to make your business smarter
or faster or adding conversation to an existing brand like you saw with the westin bot the
microsoft bot framework has everything you need to get your bot stocking?
Let me give you an introduction.
If you've already got a bot the microsoft bot framework can seamlessly connect that bots
as users on skype slack telegram sms email and more.
Don't have a bot
our open source bot builder sdk available on github has everything you need to give your
node dot js or csharp based bot great dialoging conversation skills
and also makes it easy to integrate natural language processing and machine learning services coming
soon our bot directory will contain many fantastic bots written using the bot framework
including the build bot which is available to give you information about the build event like session
information nearby restaurants and more but
I'm a developer and I'm really excited to show you how easy it is to write code using the microsoft
bot framework to show you what it's like I put together a simple bot that orders me pizza from
domino's this is going to be great you're going to get to see some code and I get order myself lunch?
Here's the source code for my bot when a user sends my
bottom message the bot framework calls into this method right here and if user said
slashed order we drop into this block of code were first I put together my pizza
medium hand-tossed with spinach and mushrooms then I put that pizza into an order of
specified the delivery address and the credit card that I found.
That's a satya assures me use buying and then I place the order to
dominoes secure rest api now since I'm dealing with a credit card I don't
want don't transmit that and plain-text so I want to make sure
that's commit sent securely over secure channel
tryout our bot I'm going to show you my bots webpage in our bot directory.
Now it can be really hard to try out new bots so as part of the bot framework
we've included a reusable and secure will chat control that developers can
put in their own webpages so customers can talk directly with their bots.
Straight out of say hi to my bot and a respond if I
says such order will take just a second and there we go my orders on its way.
This is great for simple bots but interesting bots need real dialogue
and language skills that they can hold a real conversation I want my bot to be able to
excepted an order from a real customer where they can specify the size of their pizza the
toppings and more and you heard such talk about trustworthiness it's important for
robot to get the users permission before actually sends the order on its way to dominoes now this is
were a bot builder sdk really shines our bot builder sdk is available in node dot
js and csharp but I'm writing in csharp so I'll show you that.
Use our bot builder sdk I'm just going to remove the existing simple bot code
that I've got an ad in a couple of lines here.
And, then up at the top of configured the bot builder
sdk so, the my bot talks the way I want to I've added welcome message a
confirmation prompt and then actually added in the code place the order
the bot builder sdk does all the work of walking my user through filling in my
up the object that represents my pizza which are defined as a
plain csharp object with a few annotations now next we're going to actually connect my
bot to users so I'm going to go to my bots dashboard in the developed
in our developer portal in the bot framework a you can see here it's
easy to connect my bot up to services like skype slack telegram
and others we bought the bot framework to be an open platform so we include many third-party
services including pervasive services like sms which are accessible worldwide
and available even on inexpensive devices like this fourteen dollar mobile phone.
Now we're really excited to introduce the bot framework or even more excited to see the kinds of things
you write using it we have a session coming up immediately after the keynote at
eleven thirty were walk you through the process of building a conversational bot from zero to sixty
using the bot framework hope to see there are up next I like to introduce lili tang
is going to give you a sneak peek at some upcoming intelligent tools coming to the bot framework in the future.
So, as dan said I'm going to give you a sneak
peek at some tools we the experimenting with to help you build your bot sprayed.
All right so here I have
my chat control and I can type in please send me a large pepperoni pizza.
And, you can see that my bot understands the size and toppings
ask me to clarify what kind of crust I want.
Now in order to do this your bot needs to understand natural
language so as you begin before you have real users using your bot
the before you have real user response data we
provided some simple tools to help you build your natural language rules let's take a look.
All right so these are the rules behind my bot
brain just like dan showed you except we providing you why
do make them a little bit easier to read so if you look at the first rule it
matches responses such as deliver me some quantity of
some size pizza a with some kind of topping that's pretty cool right.
So, I can just click into the deliver blurb to understand it more and here you
can see that not only the word deliver triggers the verb but also order and
by so that's pretty cool too.
But, what if people use other words?
Because we mine the web and understand language things like verb
tense translation into other language common misspellings we can help
you by providing you some suggestions for synonyms.
All you need to do is click.
Select once you once.
And, you expanded dictionary really easy.
What else is great is if I have other bots like the cupcake bot that lilian
showed you earlier I can share these dictionaries across my various bots?
Now rules are great and critical for getting started but as you
start getting more and more users and more and more response data rules can
be very complex to manage and this is where we provide you with another tool.
Here we use machine learning
and deep learning to create your conversation model.
So, building upon what I just showed you we automatically add
your semantic dictionary and your rules we also make it really easy for you to upload
additional training data to get started now we know.
That people can be very unpredictable as they user bots.
So, here you can see a
user has said can you deliver three large pepperoni pizzas to my crib.
So, you're laughing so, you know, and, I know that my crib is slang for
house but the system doesn't know that so it's really easy for me if I
think it's appropriate to tag it as a location and
save so it's that easy to help teach your bot and help
become smarter and you don't need to be a data science expert in
fact you don't even really need to know how to code to help your bot improve.
So, that's pretty cool right.
All right so finally we
know intelligent systems have their limitations so here I take send me
a large pepperoni pizza a to moscone a that too.
Eric and here my body's telling me I don't understand.
And, what it can do for tasks that are rare complex?
Or just that it doesn't understand it can automatically escalate
to a person and this is something that we think is a great example of
what satya mentioned earlier to combine what people do
best with the intelligent system so let's take a look at what the worker might see.
All right so here as I'm working
the system in real time is automatically suggesting me responses and you can
see those responses below my text entry in the chat window.
And, then on the side the system
is automatically pre-filling my order form based on what it knows.
Now I can see here the system has incorrectly
classified moscone is a person so all I need to do it again is click.
Correct the annotation and save it.
The system prompts me to clarify that its moscone
center and again my suggested response is update I can just click
and enter to have to facilitate my interaction with my customer.
So, this is exciting because while working I can
continue to teach my bot without needing to know
natural language machine learning deep learning or even coding.
All of my input can make the system more intelligent and
the intelligent system can help me get my work done more effectively
that's it for my sneak peek we know we have a lot to learn.
As we continue to experiment and make we will make these tools more broadly available.
And, of course as you've already heard you can get started today with both
the bot framework that dan showed you earlier to build and connect your bot
to places people connect
skype bot tools and also cornelia is up next to show you the
new cognitive services which will help make your tools more intelligent thank you.
Thank you lili.
Ria hello everybody in a
year ago we introduced the first portfolio of intelligent services
from microsoft we had five apis for you to go use
and add intelligence to your apps.
Well, today I want to introduce you to microsoft dot com slash cognitive
our new portfolio of intelligent services and we have twenty-two
apis for you to get started with for free today.
We have apis we have apis
across vision from image to video understanding speech.
Language understanding apis.
Knowledge apis.
And, of course search apis through bing
twenty-two apis for you to get started with this is years
of machine learning and ai research from microsoft ready for you to use
at your fingertips now you can just samoa.
You can just imagine all the cool stuff you can build with these apis and to showcase what's
possible I'm going to show you a handful of demos the first
I'll show you is a quick app we put together all I need to do in
this app is either take a photo or upload some image url logistic
this desk here and use that it calls into the new vision apis and
what that is able to do is able to recognize objects in the image?
There are thousands of objects we can recognize and we also give you a confidence score if
the confidence is low, you know, we're not quite sure if for seeing what we say we're seeing if the
confidence is high you can probably take it for real.
Now it's cool we have object recognition we can take it a step further and role show you
in my next demo we can take it a step further by not just recognizing objects but also figuring
out the relationships behind them and then using natural language to create
a coherent description of what you're seeing in the image.
This is caption bot that ai and you them aware side we're going to allow you to
play with today I went in earlier picked up a couple of random images
off of bing and now let's see what our little caption bot signal to say
its thinks it's a herd of cattle standing on a dry grass field I love the fact
that it gives the vocabulary right that doesn't say group of cattle or group of animals no it's a
herd of cattle and it also sees that it's a dry grass field.
This is the mona lisa as most of you here now let's see what.
Our little caption bot can do.
All right so trips of its as I'm not really confident but I think if we have a heart
of the vinci sitting in front of the mirror and he seems neutral faced.
This goes to show you our bot wasn't taught any art so then it doesn't
recognize the masters of the renaissance of their masterpieces we haven't
shown it any of that data we've only shown it landscapes and gatherings and,
you know, your average day-to-day life to learn from.
And, I showed you this example to show just how important data is when you are
trying to take advantage of these machine learning a services an apis and
we're working on allowing you to bring your own data to these algorithms
and customize them for your needs.
Which frankly into my third demo?
This demo is a quick little app that we put together to show you a service we call
Custom recognition intelligent service it allows you to bring any audio
files and customize our speech-to-text technology that's already shipped in
products like cortana and bing so if your scenario
calls for audio that has a lot of background noise think of,
you know, a busy drive-through and you're trying to understand what you're customers ordering or think, you
know, you're trying to understand what people with heavy romanian accents like me are trying to say
well you bring those files and you're able to train the speech-to-text algorithms
to have higher precision for your scenarios what I'm showing you here is an example that we
trained with child speech and I hope the audio is hooked up because it's important to realize
just how bad the audio can be here and the difference between speech regular speech-to-text versus
cris left side shows you regular speech-to-text right side is
cris and now let's see what our system is able to recognize.
Chance like large bash.
They use case badge collects star.
We had some kids here read a book about giants and you can clearly see that cris gets
kids not talking about dancing is talking about giants and the fact that they love large bags.
No.
Thank you.
Now these demos are all fun I'm going to finish up by showing showing you a real
customer scenario witti globe is a
startup and they do real-time twitter analysis
monitoring they try to create a twitter analysis for anything from
brands to politics and I went in earlier and use the
products the dashboard that they offer their customers to actually create a dashboard for
the current presidential elections you can see them move
the entire election and this and this little blurb here the cool thing of a visual with that
it doesn't just give you these mood indicators it also offers extra of our context
like the gender of the people who tweet or their age ranges and,
creating these gender and age range indicators they actually use the vision apis
from cognitive services they use the vision apis to look at the profile image and add extra
precision to the age or the gender identification are they further
use cognitive services also filter out any kind of tweets or content
that are just irrelevant to the dashboards they are trying to create.
Now just like vidigrove who is one of the partners who has started testing our apis early on
you can go to microsoft dot com slash cognitive
today and get started for free we can't wait to see the
stuff you build with these cool apis thank you.
Thank you so much cornelia so hopefully you get
feel for the richness of these intelligent services that you can
And, now it is up to each of
faucets developers to imagine
what's possible imagine what boeing can do to
the business applications in the aerospace industry what case western
reserve can do to medical education what nasa can do
for space exploration what a fast-food restaurant can do
for order-taking through a drive-through using cris.
What a new saw organization can do to be able to interpret all
tax all images all videos on a social media stream in real time?
And, one developer
truly inspired me this last year very close to home for us at
microsoft I want to see what he dreamt of roll the video.
I'm saqib shaikh spiced
site when I was seven shortly after that I went to a school for the blind and that's way
who is continues to be talking computers and that radio open up a whole new world of ching.
Joined microsoft ten years ago as a software engineer by
love-making things which improve people's lives and one of the
things are always dreamt of since I was a university was this idea of something
back and tell you attending my but what's going on around.
I think it's a man jumping in the air doing a trick on a skateboard.
I teamed up with like-minded today is to make about which that today to and what is
around you states-based on top of the microsoft intelligence apis which
makes it so much easier to make this kind of thing the app runs on smartphones but also the on the pivot
head smartglasses when you're talking to a
bigger group tugs you can token there's no response and you think
is everyone listening greatly well or are they half-asleep and he never?
I see to faces forty-year-old man with the beard looking surprised
twenty-year-old woman looking happy the app can describe the general
age and gender of the people around me and what the relations off which is incredible?
One of things that's most useful bad the app is the ability to
read our text moi.
Could use the app on my side to take a picture of the
many and is going to guide me on how to take the correct photo
move camera to the bottom right away from the document and they will recognize the text redmi
the having ic appetizers salad ponies pizzas
pastas and years ago this was science-fiction I never thought it would be something that you
can actually do artificial intelligence days improving had to have a
faster right I'm really excited see where we can take moi?
As and today is always standing on the shoulders of giants building on top of
what went before in this case we've taken years of research from microsoft research to pull this
off I think it's a young girl throwing in orange frisbee in the dark for me it's
about taking that far-off dream and building one-step-at-a-time I think this is just the beginning.
Well-meaning it copter privilege.
To have a chance to share the stage with soggy.
And, you know, saqib took his passion his
empathy.
And, is going to change the world?
And, to me that's what build is all about he's here in
fact at build to network inspire other developers
learn himself on how to take is applications and make them better
but more importantly he's also here to teach she's got a couple
of your sessions that he's going to do as well and to me that's what makes
these developer conferences magical it is about being able to take our
passions our empathy and go after the opportunities that
we see go after the dreams that we have and what's a key was done has been
a real inspiration for me and we as developers have this tremendous opportunity
in a tremendous responsibility because not only do we get to dream
of the future we get to build the future I can wait to see
what you dream up and what you build thank you so very much have a fantastic build
faithfully?